Dallas Smythe fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Agricultural economics, 1934 - 1938; F-16-3; 12 cm of textual records
  Dallas Smythe began his involvement in the field of agricultural economics in 1934, when he worked as an extension specialist in agriculture for the College of Agriculture at the University of California, Berkeley. In this position, he studied economic outlooks for various California farm products. In 1937, he was hired as an associate economist by the U.S. Central Statistical Board, where he oversaw the collection of statistics for the U.S. Department of Agriculture. This involved the review of information collection policies and procedures, and the planning of the Census of Agriculture. Smythe left the Central Statistical Board in 1938.
  Series consists of records written or co-authored by Smythe in his positions as extension specialist in agriculture for the University of California, Berkeley, and as an economist for the U.S. Central Statistical Board. Series includes research and reports regarding various farm crops in California, and reports and chart books from the federal Census of Agriculture.
  - Economic brief presented in connection with the marketing agreement for dry edible beans produced in California, 1934; F-16-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - California dry bean outlook, 1934; F-16-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Barley statistics with special reference to California, 1934; F-16-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Report on the continuation of the Tulare Country navel orange study in 1934, F-16-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - The 1935 agricultural outlook for California, 1934; F-16-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Statistics presented in connection with a proposed marketing agreement for hops produced in California, Oregon and Washington, 1935; F-16-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Feed, 1935; F-16-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - "What if outlook" (re: California walnut situation), 1935; F-16-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Statistics presented in connection with a proposed prorate for lemons produced in California, 1935; F-16-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - The 1936 agricultural outlook for California, 1935; F-16-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Competition between linseed and other drying oils, with special reference to California, 1936; F-16-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Dry edible beans, 1936; F-16-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - The general economic outlook, 1936; F-16-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - The 1937 agricultural outlook for California, 1936; F-16-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Lima bean statistics, 1936 - 1938; F-16-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Lima price analysis reports, 1937 - 1938; F-16-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Some agricultural weights, measures and conversion factors, 1937; F-16-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Notes on the Census of Agriculture: II. a technique for regionalization of agricultural census studies, 1938; F-16-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - The federal chart book (with agricultural statistics by Dallas Smythe), 1938; F-16-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
  - Status of work of Dallas W. Smythe, 1938; F-16-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-21)
- U.S. Department of Labor (Wage and Hour Division), 1918 - 1944; F-16-4; 38 cm of textual records 46 Photographs; Physical description: 46 photographs located in F-16-4-0-5
  Dallas Smythe was hired by the U.S. Department of Labor (Wage and Hour Division) in 1938. His role in this newly-created department was to help enforce laws regarding minimum wage rates and maximum hours of allowed work. He investigated cases in which the implementation of these laws was being avoided through various means. His investigations included occupational studies of the working conditions of newspaper boys, railway porters, life-insurance salesmen, telegraph messengers, cigar factory workers, railway maintenance workers, textile workers, lumber camp workers, and others.
  Series consists of records arising from investigations conducted by the U.S. Department of Labor (Wage and Hour Division). Series includes correspondence, studies, reports, reference material, written testimony, photographs, and other materials.
  - Atlantic Coast Line Railway, 1938 - 1939; F-16-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
  - Atlantic Coast Line Railway, 1940 - 1941; F-16-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
  - Atlantic Coast Line correspondence, 1942; F-16-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
  - Atlantic Coast Line master file, 1918 - 1940; F-16-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
  - Peavy-Wilson Lumber Co. - photographs, 1941; F-16-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
    Textual records; Photographic materials
  - Peavy-Wilson Lumber Co., 1941; F-16-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-22)
  - Peavy-Wilson Lumber Co. Inc. (Dallas Smythe testimony), 1942; F-16-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Peavy-Wilson Lumber Co. correspondence, 1941 - 1942; F-16-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Deductions in the textile manufacturing industry, 1941; F-16-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Deductions in the textile manufacturing industry, 1941; F-16-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Deductions in the textile manufacturing industry, 1941; F-16-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Deductions in the textile manufacturing industry, 1941; F-16-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Report on Horton Laundry's chenille operation, 1942; F-16-4-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-23)
  - Reasonable cost of housing, 1940 - 1941; F-16-4-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Report on the economics of the newspaper industry in relation to the Fair Labour Standards Act of 1938, 1939; F-16-4-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Telegraph employees under the Fair Labor Standards Act, 1940; F-16-4-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Miscellaneous cases, 1939 - 1942; F-16-4-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Miscellaneous industries, 1941 - 1944; F-16-4-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Labour market data, 1942; F-16-4-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - Miscellaneous reports and memos, 1940 - 1942; F-16-4-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
  - War Manpower Commission, 1942; F-16-4-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 16-24)
- U.S. Federal Communications Commission, 1939 - 1948; F-16-5; 49 cm of textual records
  Smythe served as Chief Economist for the U.S. Federal Communications Commission from 1943 to 1948. In this position, he conducted an economic analysis of the telegraph industry, investigated the issues surrounding the proposed merger of Western Union and Postal Telegraph, carried out studies in farm telephone service, and held public hearings on the post war reallocation of the radio spectrum.
  Series consists of records arising from Smythe's employment at the U.S. Federal Communications Commission. Series includes publications, correspondence, and other materials.
  - Office Files, 1939 - 1948; F-16-5-1; 15 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of office records maintained by Smythe during his employment at the U.S. Federal Communications Commission. Series includes correspondence, exhibits presented to the Commission, written testimony, and some records received from the Board of War Communications.
    - Annual program of labour statistics, 1945; F-16-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Exhibits 33 through 59, introduced by Jennie Newsome, in docket No. 7982, 1946; F-16-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - FM - Analysis of applications, Senate small business release and communications release on prices and delivery dates, receiver survey, 1945 - 1947; F-16-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Federal Communications Commission labor supply survey, 1942; F-16-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Golden's telegraph paper (Government policy and the domestic telegraph industry), 1946; F-16-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Informal labor conference - telegraph mergers, 1943; F-16-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Investigation of Federal Communications Commission, 1948, 1944 - 1947; F-16-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Miscellaneous orders and notices, 1945 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Origins of Economics and Statistics Division, Federal Communications Commission, 1940 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Radio operators, 1939 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Remarks - Ohio State University - radio conference, 1948; F-16-5-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Revision of annual report forms and schedules, 1947; F-16-5-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Supplementary statement on need for deferments for men in critical occupations in the common carrier industry, 1944; F-16-5-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Telegraph - general, 1942; F-16-5-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Telegraph - mergers and labor 1/2, 1943 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-25)
    - Telegraph - mergers and labor 2/2, 1943 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Testimony (direct) by Dallas Smythe in Mayflower hearing, 1947; F-16-5-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Transcript 324 - Conference (re: revision of schedule 13, annual report form 324), 1946; F-16-5-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - WU (Western Union) - investigation master file, June 1946, 1946 - 1948; F-16-5-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
  - Publications, 1943 - 1948; F-16-5-2; 34 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of publications written or co-authored by Smythe in his position as chief economist at the U.S. Federal Communications Commission. Publications include reports, surveys, trend forecasts, studies, and statistics on the topics of radio and telegraph communications, television, and other communications industries.
    - Board of War Communications - report to subcommittee on present labor supply and future manpower requirements, 1943; F-16-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Radio operator lists, 1943; F-16-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - A survey of current collective bargaining agreements of international communications carriers, 1943; F-16-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Interim report - trends in common carrier communications of the volume of traffic in 1946, 1944; F-16-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Some aspects of the differentials in the wage rates of Western Union Corporation, 1944; F-16-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Employment and labor turnover in the telegraph and telephone Industries, June 1943-December 1944 (5 volumes), 1943 - 1944; F-16-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Public responsibility of broadcast licenses, 1945; F-16-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Forecasts of trends and development in radio broadcast services, common carrier activities, and safety and special radio services for fiscal year 1947, 1945; F-16-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Preliminary analysis of factors affecting prices at which standard broadcast stations are sold, 1945; F-16-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Labor in international communications common carriers, 1945; F-16-5-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Rate of return study, 1945; F-16-5-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-26)
    - Attitudes of rural people toward radio service - Bureau of Agricultural Economics study, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Color TV study (Some replies to Federal Communications Commission questionnaire on production and pricing of television receivers and transmitters), 1946; F-16-5-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - A preliminary analysis of the historical relationship of broadcast advertising revenue to radio families and general business activity, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - An analysis of the historical relationship between gross national product and revenues of various rapid intercity communications industries, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Description of Federal Communications Commission radio survey, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey (appendices to description of Federal Communications Commission radio survey), 1946; F-16-5-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. I: total - all areas, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. II: types of service areas; part 1 - tables 1-17, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. II: types of service areas; part 2 - tables 18-35, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. II: types of service areas; part 3 - tables 36-52, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. III: regions; part 1 - tables 1-17, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. III: regions; part 2 - tables 18-35, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 1 - tables 1-4, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 2 - tables 5-8, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 16-27)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 3 - tables 9-12, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 4 - tables 13-17, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 5 - tables 18-21, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 6 - tables 22-25, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. IV: types of service areas within regions; part 7 - tables 26-35, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Federal Communications Commission radio survey - vol. V: summary of sample area tables - 1 through 14, 1946; F-16-5-2-0-31 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Telephone statistics - public (3 volumes - Jan., Nov., Dec.), 1947; F-16-5-2-0-32 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - An economic study of broadcasting, 1947; F-16-5-2-0-33 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - The economic outlook for broadcasting - a report to the Commission, 1947; F-16-5-2-0-34 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Preset and prospective size of the US Active Merchant Marine fleet, 1948; F-16-5-2-0-35 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
    - Preliminary studies on some aspects of the availability of landline wire communications service, 1948; F-16-5-2-0-36 (Archival box - standard 16-28)
- Publications and presentations, 1936 - 1992; F-16-6; 1.77 m of textual records; Physical description: 7 photographs located in F-16-6-2-1
  Series consists of records relating to publications and presentations produced by Smythe in his role as a student at the University of California, Berkeley; a professor at the University of Illinois, the University of Saskatchewan at Regina, Simon Fraser University, and other universities; and as a peace activist. Series includes publications, presentations, and correspondence.
  Publications arising from Smythe's employment as an agricultural economist (at the University of California, Berkeley and at the U.S. Central Statistical Bureau), and as chief economist with the Federal Communications Commission are located in series F-16-3 (Agricultural economics) and F-16-5 (U.S. Federal Communications Commission).
  - Publications and presentations, 1936 - 1992; F-16-6-1; 1.52 m of textual records
    Subseries consists of records arising from publications and presentations produced by Dallas Smythe. Series includes his Ph.D. dissertation, journal articles, studies, speeches, prepared testimony, and other materials. Materials relate to television content analysis, satellite broadcasting and other communications technology, the effects of mass media on society, the peace movement, and other topics researched and studied by Smythe.
    - Dallas Smythe's Ph.D. dissertation: History of Transportation in the East Bay, 1936; F-16-6-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-29)
    - Proposed communications research centre - University of California, 1948; F-16-6-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Remarks at radio research panel, 1948; F-16-6-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Television position and outlook, 1949; F-16-6-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - An inventory of (non-commercial) educational radio programming, 1949; F-16-6-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Television in relation to other media and recreation in American life, 1949; F-16-6-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Use of surveys by government agencies, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - "Television" in Education and the Mass Media of Communication, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Television and the school: "see life in shadows", 1950; F-16-6-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Educational radio station programming study, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Television study: leisure time use diary, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Inventory no. 2 of educational radio station programming: analysis of 1950 programs with comparisons, 1949-1950, F-16-6-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - A national policy on television?, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Analysis of the publicity and pressures (Bowen controversy at University of Illinois), 1950; F-16-6-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - People and television: the natural history of an unfinished study, 1950; F-16-6-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - The psychology of broadcasts on tolerance, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - National Association of Educational Broadcasters questionnaire, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Directory of National Association of Educational Broadcasters member stations: AM and FM radio stations of the United States, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - A proposal for an educational television station (non-commercial) for Southern California, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Study no. 1 (New York television study), 1951; F-16-6-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 16-30)
    - Television study no. 1 report, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-21
    - Television and education (roundtable with Dallas Smythe), 1951; F-16-6-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - An analysis of television programs, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - A problem in content macro-analysis presented by the National Association of Educational Broadcasters monitoring study of New York television, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Television - boon or bane for our youth?, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - The consumer's stake in radio and television in fifteenth anniversary report, Consumers Union, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Review of British and American English since 1900, 1951; F-16-6-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Theoretical approaches to the effects of communications, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - A mid-century view of competition in the broadcasting business, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Facing facts about the broadcast business, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - What TV programming is like, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - What mass communications do for us and to us, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - The consumers' stake in radio and television, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Civilian television research - 1952 model, F-16-6-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Profitable television in Central Illinois, 1952; F-16-6-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Theoretical approaches to the effects of mass communications, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Broadcasting, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Study of music content in television and radio in the United States, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Three years of New York television, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - Portrait of an art theatre audience, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 16-31)
    - New Haven television, 1952 - 1953; F-16-6-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Interpretations of reality offered by mass media, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Reality as presented by TV, 1953; F-16-6-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - The role of film in educational television, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Who can speak to my condition? or The challenge to the Protestant churches from the radio-television audiences, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Reality as presented by television, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Draft of testimony by Dallas W. Smythe, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Colour television, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-48 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Basic issues in communications in the education of Protestant ministers (speech and published article), 1954; F-16-6-1-0-49 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Some observations on communication theory, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-50 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - TV programs we haven't seen, 1954; F-16-6-1-0-51 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Portrait of a first-run audience, 1955; F-16-6-1-0-52 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Dimensions of violence, 1955; F-16-6-1-0-53 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Draft of reply to comments (Federal Communications Commission hearings into pay TV), 1955; F-16-6-1-0-54 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - The meaning of television for America, 1956; F-16-6-1-0-55 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Work paper - a program research plan for the Broadcasting and Film Commission, 1956; F-16-6-1-0-56 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Some theory on power, with a note on communications policy, 1956; F-16-6-1-0-57 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - The position of pay TV, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-58 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - The readership of Family Weekly in Champaign, Illinois, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-59 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - The structure and policy of electronic communication, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-60 (Archival box - standard 16-32)
    - Pay TV: an attempted revolution within the cultural industry, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-61 (Archival box - standard 16-32)